trendkite.com 2019-12-07

# Privacy Policy

Whats New  |  Download PDF Version

**These terms apply to your use of our public-facing marketing site, www.trendkite.com, including regional variations. If you’re looking for the terms that apply to our paid software-as-a-service, please click here:TrendKite App Privacy Policy.**

Welcome to TrendKite, and thanks for visiting us! We put together this privacy notice to let you know how we collect and process your personal data when you visit our company sites, as well as your privacy rights and how the law protects you.

We’ve done our best to keep this notice simple to read. That said, sometimes our lawyers can get pretty wordy. There’s a glossary at the bottom of the page to help you figure out some of the terms we use. As laws evolve, we may update this notice. The latest date of any updates will always be displayed at the top of this page. You can see a summary of the latest changes and prior versions by clicking the “What’s New” link at the top of the page. If you want to keep a copy of this notice for your records, you can download a PDF version at the link at the top of this page.

If you have questions about this privacy notice or want to exercise any of your legal rights regarding your personal data, please drop us a line at [privacy@cision.com](mailto:privacy@cision.com). You can also send our legal team some snail mail at Legal Department, TrendKite Inc., 800 Brazos St., Ste. 340, Austin, TX 78701. Please include your name, address and any other information necessary to respond to your question or request.

**1\. WHO WE ARE**

TrendKite Inc. and TrendKite Ltd. make up the TrendKite group of companies. This privacy notice is issued on behalf of the TrendKite group, so when we mention “TrendKite,” “we,” “us” or “our” in this privacy notice, we are referring to the relevant company responsible for processing your data. TrendKite Inc. is the controller and responsible for our sites.

**2.**   **THE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU**

When we say personal data, we’re referring to any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. This doesn’t include any information that’s been anonymized by removing identifying information.

**Data we collect** : When you visit our sites or request information from us, we may collect, use, store and transfer the following kinds of personal data about you:

  * **Identity Data** : first name, last name, company name
  * **Contact Data** : email address
  * **Technical Data** : location, internet protocol (IP) address, browser information, time zone setting, operating system and other information on the devices you use to access our sites
  * **Profile Data** : interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses
  * **Usage Data** : information about how you use our websites, content and services
  * **Marketing and Communications Data** : your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties

We also collect **Aggregated Data** , which is statistical or demographic data we derive from combining your information with data from other users (this is not considered personal data). For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data with Usage Data from other visitors to determine the percentage of users accessing a specific site feature.

**Data we don’t collect** : We don’t collect any Special Categories of Personal Data or any information about criminal convictions and offences. Since we’re in the business of selling software-as-a-service to communications pros, we don’t knowingly market to children or collect their personal data.

**3\. HOW WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We use the following methods to collect data from and about you:

  * **Direct interactions** : You may give us your Identity and Contact Data by filling out forms or corresponding with us, including providing personal data when you ask for information about our products or services, subscribe to our newsletter, download content, request marketing to be sent to you, fill out a survey or give us some feedback.
  * **Automated technologies or interactions** : As you interact with our website, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns by using cookies, server logs and other similar technologies. We may also receive Technical Data from third parties if you visit other websites.
  * **Third parties or publicly available sources** : We may receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources, including analytics and search providers like Google, advertising networks, data brokers or aggregators, and publicly availably sources.

We may allow links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications on our sites, which may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We don’t control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements, but we definitely encourage you to look for them and read them

**4\. HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We’ll only use your personal data when we’re allowed to by law and only for the reasons we collected it. Some of those reasons are performing a contract with you, when it’s necessary for our legitimate interests (and your interests and rights don’t override ours), and when we need to comply with legal or regulatory obligations. We’ll only use your personal data for the reasons we collected it, though we may use it for compatible purposes if we reasonably think we need to do so. If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and explain our reasons for doing so.

Here’s how we use the personal data that we collect:

  * We use your Identity, Contact, Profile, Usage, Marketing and Communications, and Technical Data to deliver relevant marketing content to you and measure and understand its effectiveness. This is necessary for our legitimate interests, like studying how customers use our products and services so we can develop our marketing strategies and grow our business.
  * We use your Usage and Technical Data to perform data analytics that help us improve our sites, products and services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences. This is necessary for our legitimate interests in defining the types of customers for our products and services, keeping our website updated and relevant, developing marketing strategies and growing our business.
  * We use your Identity, Contact, Profile, and Marketing and Communications Data to manage our relationship with you, including notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policies or asking you to take a survey or provide feedback. This is necessary to comply with our legal obligations and for our legitimate interests in keeping our records updated and studying how customers use our products and services to develop our marketing strategies and grow our business.
  * We use your Identity, Contact, and Technical Data to administer and protect our business and this website, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data. This is necessary for us to comply with our legal obligations and for our legitimate interests in running our business, providing administration and IT services, maintaining the security of our network and preventing fraud, and in the event of a reorganization or restructuring.
  * We use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data to make suggestions and recommendations to you about products or services that may be of interest to you. This is necessary for our legitimate interest in developing our products and services, refining our marketing strategies, and growing our business.

We’ll send you marketing communications if you’ve requested information from us (including registering for a webinar, downloading content or asking for a demo) or purchased our products or services, unless you’ve opted out of receiving our marketing. If you want to opt out of communications from us or our third parties, follow the opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you or contact us at [marketing-admin@cision.com](mailto:marketing-admin@cision.com). Even if you opt out, we may still use your personal data and contact you if you’re a customer.

**5\. COOKIES**

We use cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies on our sites to distinguish you from other visitors, analyze trends, administer our sites, track usage, and gather demographic information about our visitors. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent from a web server and stored on your device. Third parties (like advertising networks and web traffic analyzers) may also use cookies on our sites, over which we have no control. You can block cookies using the settings on your browser. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies you may not be able to access all or parts of our site. **By continuing to browse our site, you are agreeing to our use of cookies.**

**6\. DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We may have to share your personal data with Internal Third Parties, External Third Parties, or third parties as part of a merger, acquisition or similar corporate transaction. All third parties that we share your personal data with are expected to respect your personal data and treat it in accordance with applicable law. We only allow third party service providers to process your personal data for specific purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

**7\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS**

If you’re in the European Economic Area (EEA), we transfer your data outside the EEA. When we do, we make sure your personal data is protected. For some service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, [click here](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en). For service providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US. For more information about Privacy Shield, [click here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/Program-Overview).

**8\. DATA SECURITY**

We have appropriate administrative, physical, and technical safeguards in place to keep your personal information from wandering out of our control or being inappropriately accessed. This includes limiting access to your personal data and giving specific instructions on how to use your personal data. If we suspect your personal data has gone astray, we’ll let you know as soon as possible and notify any applicable regulator where we are legally required to do so.

**9\. DATA RETENTION**

We keep your personal data only as long as we need it to achieve the purposes for which we collected it. When deciding how long to keep your data, we consider the amount, nature and sensitivity of the data, the potential risk of harm if it’s accessed or used inappropriately, the purposes for which we collect and process it and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and any applicable legal requirements.

**10\. YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS**

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data. You can exercise any of your rights by contacting us at [privacy@cision.com](mailto:privacy@cision.com). We may need to ask you for specific information to confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data or exercise your other rights. If you’re in the EEA:

  * You can **request access** to your personal data to receive a copy of the personal data we hold.
  * You can **request correction** of the personal data that we hold about you.
  * You can **request erasure** of your personal data, though we may not be able to comply with your request if we have specific legal reasons (if that’s the case, we’ll let you know as soon as possible).
  * You can **object to us processing** your personal data, though we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your interests (such as performance of a contract with you).
  * You can **request restrictions** on processing your personal data.
  * You can **request the transfer** of your personal data that was automatically collected with your consent or used to perform a contract with you, in which case we’ll provide your data in a structured, commonly-used, machine-readable format.
  * You can **withdraw consent** at any time for personal data for which we are relying on your consent to process, though this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing that was carried out before you withdrew your consent.

  **GLOSSARY   **

Here’s a short guide to some of the terms we used in this privacy notice:

  * **Legitimate interest** means our interest in conducting and managing our business to give you the best products and services and providing you with a secure experience when you visit our sites. We balance the impacts on you and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests.
  * **Performance of a contract** means processing your data when we have a contract with you and it’s necessary for us to perform our obligations or take certain steps before entering into such a contract.
  * **Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation** means processing your personal data when we need to comply with our legal or regulatory obligations.
  * **Special Categories of Personal Data** means details about your race, ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life or orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, or health, genetic or biometric data.
  * **Internal Third Parties** means other companies in the TrendKite group that may act as joint controllers or processors and provide IT and system administration services.
  * **External Third Parties** means service providers who provide IT and system administration services and act as processors; professional advisers acting as processors or joint controllers, including our contractors, consultants, lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers; regulators and other government authorities acting as processors or joint controllers who require reporting of processing activities.
